

JUNIOR FRONT END DEVELOPER

### **Details**

22 Guardians Close Clitheroe 0778644103 dickinsonjames@hotmail.co.uk

### Skills

Inquisitivness

Good work ethic

Pro-active

Initiative and Problem-solving Abilities

**Effective Time Management** 

### **Profile**

Junior Web Developer with experience in all stages of front end web development. Knowledgeable in user interface, testing, and debugging processes. Bringing forth experience in design, installation, testing and implementation.. Self-taught knowledge through CodeAcademy and freeCodeCamp.org in an assortment of languages, including JS, Node, Vue, HTML and Tailwind. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate in a team setting. Hard-working pro-active individual, self-studied web-design along side full time work and looking after my one year old daughter. Currently studying as part of CODE- Cohort 3 based out of Lancaster to further knowledge and learn new skills from people who have been there and done it!

# **Employment History**

### Weighbridge Technician, Heidelberg Cement, Clitheroe

OCTOBER 2019 - PRESENT

- Worked well independently and as part of a team to solve problems. Dealt with recent Carlisle train derailment.
- Only technician in the history of the company to be sponsored for the Fleet Manager CPC and FORS operator courses. Both qualifications gained.
- Experienced in conducting Root Cause Analysis and new system integration . SAP ERP and SynchroTess fleet management system implemented.
- Managed a team of drivers and ensured they achieved KPI's around Working Time Directives, speed policies and Driver Hours. Cross-referenced on work note versus tachograph readings.

### Warehouse Supervisor, Trutex Ltd., Clitheroe

APRIL 2015 - OCTOBER 2019

- Started as a general operative and then progressed to sales representative, warehouse administrator, team leader and then finally warehouse supervisor. Left due to no further progression being available.
- Worked as part of a team and then lead my own department. In my final year
  we broke all KPI records. This was achieved by my analysis and streamlining
  of processes, a new process of picking orders, the cultivation of a good team
  culture and an understanding of managing individuals and their different
  motivations.
- Managed third party satellite warehouses via phone email and in person. This
  included importing the stock in, QC, receipting goods and then shipping out.
  These were predominantly 40 foot shipping containers of mixed SKU blazers
  and accounted for the bulk of the revenue for the business.

# Bar Manager and Museum Assistant, Townley Hall (Burnley Borough Council), Burnley

JUNE 2013 - FEBRUARY 2016

- Managed the events team for functions within the hall, conducted viewings for prospective clients.
- Worked as a tour guide and took enquiries from the general public.

### Work Placements, Various, Manchester

APRIL 2010 - DECEMBER 2012

 Undertook three work placements at Kenworthys Barristers Chambers, Turner Parkinson LLP and Forbes Solicitors.

# **Education**

LLB Law, The University of Chester, Chester

## Various, Clitheroe Royal Grammar School and Sixth Form, Clitheroe

SEPTEMBER 2002 - JUNE 2009

11 GCSE's and 4 A-levels

## **Extra-curricular activities**

Away from work I have just finished 4 years as Clitheroe Rugby Club 1st XV Captain, a role i was voted into unanimously year on year. I took the decision to step down due to the birth of my daughter Elodie. I am a keen chef and enjoy reading across an array of genres. As seen through the rest of my C.V. I enjoy constant progression and am naturally inquisitive which brought me to learning web design. I have always had an interest in computing and in all roles I have demonstrable experience working with I.T. and its various facets. My goal is to earnestly pursue a career in the tech sector and would love to do so with yourselves

## References

Joe Bloggs from AoR AoR | AoR

Andrew Smith from AoR AoR | AoR